<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE SCOPE_NOTE
  SYSTEM "scope_note.dtd">
<SCOPE_NOTE LNG="en" VERSION="4.22"><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>08133</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>In economics, goods can vary according to the utility they provide and the needs they satisfy. Common goods are tangible, but certain classes of goods, such as information, take only intangible forms. Free goods, such as air, are naturally abundant and require no conscious effort to obtain, while economic goods are scarce relative to their demand and require human effort. Consumer or final goods are items that are ultimately consumed, and intermediate goods are needed as inputs in their production. Private goods are things that are owned by people, and commercial goods are tangible products that are produced and then made available for use in a commercial industry.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1005</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Not to be confused with financing of the EU budget which covers EU resources or incomes.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1015</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Indirect tax on the manufacture or sale of certain products.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1087</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Territorial collectivities of the French Republic created in 1946 and replaced in 2003 by the Overseas Collectivities (COM).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1089</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>As of 1 January 2016, the region of Franche-Comté was incorporated into the region of Bourgogne-Franche-Comté.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1094</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Replaced the Latin American Free Trade Association (LAFTA) in 1981.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1105</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>115</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>For decision-making body in an EU institution or body, use  "decision-making body (EU)".</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1150</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>For the influence of geography on the domestic and foreign policy of States, use geopolitics.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>118</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>In November 2001, the Council for Cultural Cooperation (CCC) was divided into four steering committees: the Steering Committee for Education (CDED), the Steering Committee for Higher Education and Research (CDESR), the Steering Committee for Culture (CDCULT) and the Steering Committee for Cultural Heritage (CDPAT).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1191</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1194</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>The G-10 is a body within the International Monetary Fund (IMF) consisting of the Ministers of Finance and Central Bank Governors of the world’s most industrialised nations. It comprises the countries of the “Group of Seven” (US, Japan, Canada, France, Germany, Italy and the UK), plus Belgium, the Netherlands, Sweden and Switzerland.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>120</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>A now obsolete organisation created on 14 June 1966 by the governments of Australia, Japan, South Korea, South Vietnam, the Republic of Korea, Malaysia, New Zealand and the Philippines. It was dissolved in 1975 as a result of disagreement among the members over the recognition of the People’s Republic of China.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1201</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Producer organisations can group themselves into associations of producer organisations and into inter-branch organisations.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>122</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1235</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>As of 1 January 2016, the region of Upper Normandy was incorporated into the region of Normandie.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1254</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Special Administrative Region of China since 1 July 1997.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1277</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for any aspect relating to methods and problems connected with animal nutrition. For the feedingstuffs themselves, use the specific term "animal feedingstuffs".</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1279</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>From release 4.7, for preference use "food safety".</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>130</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1308</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use only for the State which existed until 3 October 1990, the date of German unification.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1311</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Internal tax to which the staff of the European civil service are subject.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1318</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for the Federal Republic of Germany since the end of the Second World War and for the whole of Germany since reunification on 3 October 1990.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1430</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>On 1 January 2016, the region of Alsace was incorporated into the region of Grand Est.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1433</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Fixed routes and facilities used in transport. Use in connection with the mode of transport concerned.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1460</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Should preferably be used in conjunction with the EU policy or sector concerned.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1464</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for the various integration projects undertaken by the European States in the context of building a Europe of the Communities or together with other European organisations, such as the Council of Europe.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>15008</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>These grounds may include but are not limited to those protected by Art. 19 of the Treaty on the Functioning of the EU: sex, racial or ethnic origin, religion or belief, disability, age or sexual orientation.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1505</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Until 31.01.2020 regions of the United Kingdom were included among the regions of EU Member States.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1549</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>In the context of a monetary penalty imposed by a Commission decision on an undertaking for a violation of EU competition rules, use "sanction (EU)".</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1583</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>As of 1 January 2016, the region of Languedoc-Roussillon was incorporated into the region of Occitanie</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1592</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for national laws, especially American and British. Do not use in the context of Community competition policy; use control of restrictive practices instead.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>16</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>The European Commission on Human Rights was a special tribunal that operated between 1953 and 1998 and determined the admissibility of a complaint to the European Court of Human Rights. In 1998, protocol 11 to the European Convention on Human Rights abolished the commission and enlarged the European Court of Human Rights.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1634</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Not to be confused with labour mobility.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1658</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1666</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>As of 1 January 2016, the region of Limousin was incorporated into the region of Nouvelle-Aquitaine.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1702</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>On 1 January 2016, the region of Lorraine was incorporated into the region of Grand Est.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1716</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Special Administrative Region of China since 20 December 1999.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1759</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>If necessary, combine with the descriptors used for the affected organ or for the tropical or endemic nature of the disease.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>17665</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Not to be confused with property right (ownership).</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1786</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use specific terms.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1788</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>If possible, combine the concept ‘agricultural market’ with the appropriate market sector(s)</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1789</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use to annotate resources covering agricultural markets in the EU. If possible, combine the concept ‘EU agricultural market’ with the appropriate market sector(s).</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1792</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Do not restrict usage to the EU.</SN><HN>In the EU context, the concept "common market" is now only used historically and has been replaced by single market.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1794</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1795</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Combine with the relevant market sector(s). Do not confuse with "single market".</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>18</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>If necessary, use in association with the area of activity concerned.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1806</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use in association with country concerned.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1839</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Not to be confused with reference materials used in librarianship.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1844</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1847</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>187</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1903</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Refers to the part of Oceania situated in the North Pacific, comprising some 2000 islands. For the country, use the descriptor "Federated States of Micronesia".</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1904</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>As of 1 January 2016, the region of Midi-Pyrénées was incorporated into the region of Occitanie.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1905</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Until 31.01.2020 regions of the United Kingdom were included among the regions of EU Member States.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1906</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Until 31.01.2020 regions of the United Kingdom were included among the regions of EU Member States.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1912</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Not to be confused with family reunification.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1942</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The acronym 'LGBTIQ' may evolve over time to include additional letters to represent other identities. This concept aims to cover all relevant identities and orientations not included in the acronym.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1946</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Refers to the ability of individual workers to move around within the labour market. Not to be confused with free movement of workers.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2011</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for any collective action promoting greater social justice.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2034</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The rights and duties of nationals vary from state to state, with the result that in some states 'citizenship' is synonymous with 'nationality', while in others it is not. Where a distinction is made, it is usually based on the fact that citizenship confers political rights. For ethnicity, use the concept 'ethnic group' (1202).</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2062</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Not to be confused with "cost of living".</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2070</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Defence pact between Australia, the United States and New Zealand.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2075</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>As of 1 January 2016, the region of Nord-Pas-de-Calais was incorporated into the region of Hauts-de-France.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2079</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>210</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for cooperation between European countries outside the EU context.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2102</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Organisation created in June 1996 in Antananarivo and dissolved on 25 March 1985. Its activities fall within the remit of the Organisation of African Unity (OAU), which became the African Union in 2002.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2106</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN><HN>On 14 December 1960, 20 countries originally signed the Convention on the Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2116</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Replaced the Organisation of Central American States (OCAS) in 1991 and led to the creation of the Central American Common Market (CACM).</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2117</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2119</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2148</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2153</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Until 30.6.2009: Office for Official Publications of the European Communities.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2173</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Combine with the relevant market sector(s).</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2183</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Treaty of military alliance signed in 1955 by the European Communist states under the influence of the Soviet Union. It was dissolved in 1991.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2189</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>For the names of international organisations refer to field 76.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2200</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2201</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Defensive alliance formed on 8 September 1954 between Australia, the United States, France, the United Kingdom, New Zealand, Pakistan, the Philippines and Thailand. It was dissolved in 1977.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2202</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Pan-African organisation which replaced the Organisation of African Unity (OAU) on 9 July 2002.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>22073</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Forms of protest include writing letters to representatives, signing online petitions, attending rallies, boycotting products, setting fires (incendiarism), and taking direct action.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2243</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>The origins of the European Parliament lie in the Common Assembly of the European Coal and Steel Community (ECSC), which became the common assembly of the three supranational European communities that existed until 1957.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2244</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use in association with country concerned.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>226</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Should preferably be used in conjunction with the policy or sector concerned.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2290</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Until 31.01.2020 regions of the United Kingdom were included among the regions of EU Member States.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2291</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Political representation comprising the countries of Eastern and Central Europe which were under Soviet domination from the end of the Second World War until the collapse of the Soviet communist system in 1989-1991.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2296</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>For names of countries and territories, see microthesaurus 7241 overseas countries and territories.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2328</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>As of 1 January 2016, the region of Aquitaine was incorporated into the region of Nouvelle-Aquitaine.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>23344</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The services can include activities such as marketing or sales activities.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2364</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which cover the entire range of products, otherwise use a more specific descriptor.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2377</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>As of 1 January 2016, the region of Picardy was incorporated into the region of Hauts-de-France.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2392</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Plan for cooperative economic and social development in Asia and the Pacific.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2439</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>As of 1 January 2016, the region of Poitou-Charentes was incorporated into the region of Nouvelle-Aquitaine</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2516</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Should preferably be used in conjunction with the policy or sector concerned.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2526</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use in a general sense, not in relation to an identified noise source.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>255</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Created in 1952, this EU institution, which has its seat in Luxembourg, consists of three courts: the Court of Justice, the General Court (created in 1988) and the Civil Service Tribunal (created in 2004). The name "Court of Justice of the European Communities" was replaced by "Court of Justice of the European Union" when the Lisbon Treaty came into force on 1 December 2009.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>256</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Before 1.12.2009: ‘Court of Auditors of the European Communities’.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>258</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Not to be confused with the International Criminal Tribunal for Rwanda, the International Criminal Tribunal for the former Yugoslavia or the International Criminal Court.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2588</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for State authorities or bodies and for local and regional authorities, taken as a whole.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2592</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>The ECSC Treaty expired on 23 July 2002.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2639</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>For national prices, use prices of agricultural produce.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2652</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use in opposition to wholesale price, otherwise use consumer price.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2699</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>In civil, commercial and social matters.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2718</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with products originating from fishing. Not to be confused with "fishery resources", which refers to existing resources.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2734</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which cover the entire range of products, otherwise use a more specific descriptor.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2735</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which cover the entire range of products, otherwise use a more specific descriptor.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2736</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which cover the entire range of products, otherwise use a more specific descriptor.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2737</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which cover the entire range of products, otherwise use a more specific descriptor.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>274</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Not to be confused with "standard of living".</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2755</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>This concept has been replaced by “hygiene product” (26526).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2763</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which cover the entire range of products, otherwise use a more specific descriptor.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2767</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which cover the entire range of products, otherwise use a more specific descriptor.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2773</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Pharmaceutical product is what is manufactured/administered to the patient (the tablets with their ingredients i.e. what exists in reality) and the medicinal product is a concept that summarises it from an authorisation/entitlement perspective (the main ingredient, the form, the amount, the authorisation details).</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2820</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Autonomous entity of the Kingdom of the Netherlands.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2829</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Founded in 1975 from the merger of the European Space Research Organisation (ESRO) and the European Launcher Development Organisation (ELDO).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2894</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use in connection with the institution concerned.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2919</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Not to be confused with ecology which is the study of the interrelationships between living organisms and their environment.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2926</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use in association with the organisation concerned.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2927</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use in association with the institution concerned.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2939</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for a request to an administrative authority to cancel, change or withdraw a decision taken by the administration. Not to be confused with an action brought before an administrative court.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2941</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Action against the Council or the Commission for refraining to pronounce judgment in matters within their jurisdiction.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2967</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Preferential treatment given to goods produced in the European Community so as to encourage a Member State to buy from its partners rather than on the world market.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3060</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Not to be confused with a “joint venture”, an “economic interest grouping” or a “mixed-ownership company”.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3087</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Introduced by the joint declaration of the European Parliament, the Council and the Commission, adopted on 4 March 1975, for the purpose of seeking agreement between Parliament and the Council. Use of this procedure was limited to "Community acts of general application which have appreciable financial implications, and of which the adoption is not required by virtue of acts already in existence".</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3102</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use in association with the institution concerned.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3107</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use in association with the type of transport concerned.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3158</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Not to be confused with landslide which refers to mass wasting.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3171</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Cancelled in 1987 and replaced by the Combined Nomenclature.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3209</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Collective relations between employers and employees. For individual relations, use "personnel administration".</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3223</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Formely used for relations between the two blocs, this expression may still be used in the context of the new relations between the West and the countries of the former Eastern bloc.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3234</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for relations between Member States. For relations between a Member State and the European Union, use "European Union membership".</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3238</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Historical concept valid before the introduction of the Euro.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3258</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Not to be confused with EU financing which covers EU expenditures.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3272</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for national agricultural prices. Within the framework of the CAP use farm prices.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3290</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>To be applied to a branch of industry or at an inter-industrial level. Do not use for the internal reorganisation of a company.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3299</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Do not confuse with EU market.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3307</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>When referring to the artificial reproduction of animals, use “artificial insemination”.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3308</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>When referring to the artificial insemination of humans, use “artificial reproduction”.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>333</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Autonomous entity of the Kingdom of the Netherlands since 10.10.2010 (Netherlands Antilles dissolved).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3381</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>British Crown dependency. Not part of the United Kingdom, but depends on it in matters concerning external relations. Not part of the European Union, but is associated with it through Protocol 3 to the United Kingdom’s Act of Accession.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3388</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use only for the region which existed until 1995, afterwards use descriptors "Ceuta" or "Melilla".</SN><HN>Ceuta and Melilla are autonomous cities since 13 March 1995.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3396</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Until 31.01.2020 regions of the United Kingdom were included among the regions of EU Member States.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3397</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Until 31.01.2020 regions of the United Kingdom were included among the regions of EU Member States.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3398</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Until 31.01.2020 regions of the United Kingdom were included among the regions of EU Member States.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3399</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Until 31.01.2020 regions of the United Kingdom were included among the regions of EU Member States.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3417</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for the requisitioning of staff in order to provide a minimum service in the event of disputes or strikes.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3461</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use in connection with the countries concerned.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3467</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Includes treaties, codes of conduct, resolutions, plans of action and declarations of inter-governmental organisations. Use in association with organisation concerned.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3470</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use in association with the organisation concerned.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3476</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use in association with country concerned.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>349</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use in connection with the institution concerned.</SN><HN>With the entry into force of the Treaty of Lisbon (1.12.2009), decisions no longer need necessarily to be specifically addressed. They have therefore acquired a wider scope and have replaced, in particular, all the instruments formerly used for the CFSP.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3501</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>This designation shall not be construed as recognition of a State of Palestine and is without prejudice to the individual positions of the EU Member States on this issues.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3521</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>If necessary, use in association with the State concerned.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3540</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Not to be confused with "posted worker" used for staff being sent abroad by their employer for a project.</SN><SN>Not to be confused with migrant worker.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3627</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Do not confuse with "business cluster".</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3659</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for income of individuals or undertakings, otherwise use national income.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3666</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>With the entry into force of  amending the Community trade mark regulation on 23 March, OHIM became the European Union Intellectual Property Office, and the Community trade mark became the European Union trade mark.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3675</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Group of States which, after taking part in the 1967 Algiers Conference to prepare the Unctad assembly, compiled a list of requirements of underdeveloped countries.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3676</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>The Contadora Group was created in 1983 by the Foreign Ministers of Mexico, Venezuela, Colombia and Panama, and was incorporated into the Rio Group in 1987. Use “Rio Group”.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3708</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Secretariat of the International Labour Organisation (ILO).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3714</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>On 1 January 2016, the region of Rhône-Alpes was incorporated into the region of Auvergne-Rhône-Alpes.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3722</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Superseded the WAEC (West African Economic Community) and the WAMU (West African Monetary Union) in 1995. The name WAEC was adopted in 1970 following the reorganisation of the CUWAS (Customs Union of West African States), which was created in 1959.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3774</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>The United Kingdom ceased to be a Member State of the European Union on 31.01.2020.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3780</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Until 31.01.2020 regions of the United Kingdom were included among the regions of EU Member States.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>37846</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3813</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Pharmaceutical product is what is manufactured/administered to the patient (the tablets with their ingredients ie what exists in reality) and the medicinal product is a concept that summarises it from an authorisation/entitlement perspective (the main ingredient, the form, the amount, the authorisation details).</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3854</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use in the case of professions, otherwise in a more general context use the descriptor "labour force".</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3866</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Do not confuse with "EU restrictive measure". Sanction (EU) involves measures imposed on EU Member States that breach core EU principles.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4014</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>As of the entry into force of the Lisbon Treaty (01.12.2009), use decision (EU).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4015</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use in association with the institution concerned.</SN><HN>With effect from the entry into force of the Treaty of Lisbon (1.12.2009), use directive (EU).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4020</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>As of the entry into force of the Lisbon Treaty (1.12.2009), use recommendation (EU).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4022</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>As of the entry into force of the Lisbon Treaty (1.12.2009), use  regulation (EU) .</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4035</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>As of the entry into force of the Lisbon Treaty (1.12.2009), use Accession Treaty (EU).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4040</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use in association with the type of relation or agreement concerned.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4046</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Association which was disbanded on 31 December 1998.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4054</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>New designation for the European System for the International Clearing of Vacancies and Applications for Employment, brought in as part of the renewal process and approved by the Council in 1993.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4063</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with the advantages or disadvantages of membership of the European Union.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4065</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Since the Lisbon Treaty came into force (1.12.2009), common positions concerning the area of freedom, security and justice and the common foreign and security policy have been replaced by Council decisions. Use decision (UE).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4066</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Since the Lisbon Treaty came into force (1.12.2009), joint actions concerning the CFSP have been replaced by Council decisions. Use decision (EU).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4069</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4070</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Project launched in the 1970s to coordinate Member States’ foreign policies. EPC is incorporated into the Treaty on European Union and enshrined in the “common foreign and security policy”. Use “CFSP”.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4074</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Not to be confused with the management of financial risks or business risks.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4080</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>These come from the application of the common customs tariff to imports from third countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4099</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>This consists of activities performed in order to meet people's needs. Services are provided in the sectors such as transport, communication, trade, municipal management, healthcare, education, administration, judiciary, finance, insurance and personal services.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4136</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for the body providing a service. Not to be confused with the descriptor "services of general interest".</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4175</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Not to be confused with “head of State”.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4183</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use to describe the state of the European Union at a specific time - usually in relation to recent events, current situation, and future prospects.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4237</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Short-term Community financing intended to meet financial requirements resulting from a temporary deficit in the balance of payments.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4247</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>System of loans or gifts made to ACP States in order to remove the effects of market fluctuation and production risks upon agricultural export receipts.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>427</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Involves structural changes in the economy; for increased output of goods and services alone, use "Economic growth"</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4271</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use this concept for questions concerning staff regulations and rules for members of the civil service.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>428</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Created in 1958 as the European Nuclear Energy Agency, the organisation was officially renamed the Nuclear Energy Agency in 1972 in order to reflect its international status.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4304</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use also for EU bodies.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>435098</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>For documents relating to human therapeutic cloning, combine "human cloning" with "stem cell".</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4351</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>The official name of the Kingdom of Swaziland was changed to the Kingdom of Eswatini, or Eswatini, in April 2018.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>435265</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>For the geographical distribution of political processes, use political geography.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4364</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>On 1 January 2016, the region of Auvergne was incorporated into the region of Auvergne-Rhône-Alpes.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4370</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Replaced by ERM II (exchange rate mechanism II) at the start of Stage Three of economic and monetary union (EMU) on 1 January 1999 when the single currency was launched.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>437422</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>It replaced the MEDA and Tacis programmes on 1 January 2007.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>438855</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Term introduced by the Lisbon Treaty (1.12.2009).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>439592</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>The function of President of the European Council was instituted by the Lisbon Treaty (which came into force on 1.12.2009).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>440238</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Legislative procedure replacing the codecision procedure with effect from the entry into force of the Treaty of Lisbon (1.12.2009).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>440265</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Term introduced by the Lisbon Treaty (1.12.2009).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>440605</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Term introduced by the Lisbon Treaty (1.12.2009).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>440631</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Term introduced by the Lisbon Treaty (1.12.2009).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>440657</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Term introduced by the Lisbon Treaty (1.12.2009).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>440710</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Term introduced by the Lisbon Treaty (1.12.2009).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>441001</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>To be used together with the agency's field of competence.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4411</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use only for the State which existed until 1 January 1993, on which date the Czech and Slovak Republics separated.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4415</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use specific terms.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>443137</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>New title of the "Treaty establishing the European Community" (originally "Treaty establishing the European Economic Community") following the entry into force of the Lisbon Treaty.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4437</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Succeeded the European Payments Union and provided the institutional framework for monetary cooperation between the countries of the Organisation for European Economic Cooperation (OEEC) from 1958 to 1972.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>445178</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Term introduced by the Lisbon Treaty (1.12.2009).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>445259</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Term introduced by the Lisbon Treaty (1.12.2009).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4457</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>With effect from the entry into force of the Treaty of Lisbon (1.12.2009), use "(EU) opinion".</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4460</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Western part of the island of Timor which has been part of Indonesia since 1945.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4461</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Eastern part of the island of Timor which proclaimed itself independent on 20 May 2002 after being occupied by Indonesia since 1975.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4479</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use the specific terms.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>447917</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>New mandate of ACER on 5 June 2019. EUR-Lex. </HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4480</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>The ECSC Treaty expired in July 2002.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4481</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Original name of the founding Treaty, as signed in Rome in 1957.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>448275</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Combine with the related sectors or industries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4483</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN><HN>Military alliance (1955-1991) which was composed of the Soviet Union, Albania (until 1968), the German Democratic Republic, Bulgaria, Hungary, Poland, Romania and Czechoslovakia.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>449</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use in association with the institution concerned.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>450</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for the respect of voting instructions given to parliamentarians by their party or parliamentary group.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>450652</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>On 1 January 2007, this fund replaced the Guarantee Section of the European Agricultural Guidance and Guarantee Fund (EAGGF).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>450658</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>On 1 January 2007, this fund replaced the Guidance Section of the European Agricultural Guidance and Guarantee Fund (EAGGF).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>450953</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Established in July 2008 following the merger of the African Court of Justice and the African Court on Human and Peoples' Rights.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>451885</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Autonomous entity of the Kingdom of the Netherlands since 10.10.2010 (Netherlands Antilles dissolved).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>451912</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Since the dissolution of the Netherlands Antilles on 10.10.2010, Bonaire, Saint Eustatius and Saba have gained the status of autonomous special municipalities of the Netherlands.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>451941</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>British Crown dependency. Not part of the United Kingdom, but depends on it in matters concerning external relations. Not part of the European Union, but is associated with it through Protocol 3 to the United Kingdom’s Act of Accession.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>451991</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>British Crown dependency. Not part of the United Kingdom, but depends on it in matters concerning external relations. Not part of the European Union, but is associated with it through Protocol 3 to the United Kingdom’s Act of Accession.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>452085</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Replaced the Financial Instrument for Fisheries Guidance (FIFG) in 2007 and is followed by the European Maritime and Fisheries Funds (EMFF) for the period 2014 – 2020.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4524</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Agreement concerning the international textile trade.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4543</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Only to be used for documents of a very general nature, otherwise choose a more specific descriptor.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4580</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Türkiye obtained candidate status following the European Council meeting in Helsinki in December 1999.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4586</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>The Central African Economic and Monetary Community (CAEMC) was established in 1994 and encompasses the activities of the Central African Monetary Union (CAMU) and the Central African Customs and Economic Union (CACEU). It comprises Cameroon, the Central African Republic, Congo, Gabon, Equatorial Guinea and Chad, and its defining feature is that its members recognise the same unit of currency (the CFA franc).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4587</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4590</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN><HN>WEU ceases to exist as a Treaty-based International Organisation on 30 June 2011.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4597</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>WEU ceases to exist as a Treaty-based International Organisation on 30 June 2011</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4603</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Created in 1950 by 18 member countries of the Organisation for European Economic Cooperation (OEEC), it was dissolved in 1958 and replaced by the European Monetary Agreement.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4607</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4610</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Intergovernmental programme for cooperation in the field of scientific and technological information.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4618</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for the growth of cities, both in number of inhabitants and in territorial extent, and for the consequences of this growth on the way of life.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4620</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use only for the State which existed until the break-up of the Soviet Union.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4675</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The concept has been replaced by “audit” (4675).</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4690</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4748</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>If necessary, use in association with imports or exports.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>47644</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The categories of building performance include quality, resource savings and workload capacity.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4775</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>On May 22, 1990, the Yemen Arab Republic and the People's Democratic Republic of Yemen (Democratic Yemen) merged to form a new country, the Republic of Yemen (YEMEN)</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4776</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Used until May 21, 1990. On May 22, 1990, merged with the Yemen.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4777</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Until 31.01.2020 regions of the United Kingdom were included among the regions of EU Member States.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4824</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>As of 1 January 2016, the region of Lower Normandy was incorporated into the region of Normandie.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4828</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Agreement under which the main exporting countries and the main importers of a commodity undertake to respect a regulation relating to the international trade in this product.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4845</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4886</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>In the EU, the internal energy market covers only electricity and gas.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4887</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use the descriptor "humanisation of work" for questions concerning the quality of life at work.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4959</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Not to be confused with two-party system.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4966</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>'Myanmar/Burma' is the form often used in Council acts and official documents. 'Myanmar' is also frequently encountered, in particular in texts originating from EEAS.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5017</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which cover the entire range of products, otherwise use a more specific descriptor.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5032</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>As of 1 January 2016, the region of Burgundy was incorporated into the region of Bourgogne-Franche-Comté.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5048</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for noise pollution from a known source, such as a vehicle, a machine, a discotheque,a motorway or an airport.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5051</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Term used until the Lisbon Treaty came into force (1.12.2009).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5070</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>When referring to customs, use "customs formalities".</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5083</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5086</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Intergovernmental economic organization (1949-91) founded by USSR, Bulgaria, Czechoslovakia, Hungary, Poland and Romania. In the course of time Albania (1949-87), GDR (1950-90), Mongolia (1962), Cuba (1972) and Vietnam (1978) took also part as well as Yugoslavia (1964) as associate member.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5087</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Intergovernmental economic organization (1949-91) founded by USSR, Bulgaria, Czechoslovakia, Hungary, Poland and Romania. In the course of time Albania (1949-87), GDR (1950-90), Mongolia (1962), Cuba (1972) and Vietnam (1978) took also part as well as Yugoslavia (1964) as associate member.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5107</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Regional cooperation organisation comprising Kenya, Uganda and Tanzania.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5131</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Procedure established by the Single European Act (1986) and replaced by the approval procedure when the Lisbon Treaty came into force (on 1.12.2009).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5146</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use to describe the state of the economy of a country, a group of countries or a region at a specific time.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5210</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>This concept has been replaced by “inland waterway transport” (4515) and “maritime transport” (4522).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5258</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>With the entry into force of the Treaty of Lisbon on 1 December 2009, the names "European Union" or "EU" have replaced "European Community", "Community" or "EC".</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>52595</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The rights and duties of nationals vary from state to state, with the result that in some states 'citizenship' is synonymous with 'nationality', while in others it is not. Where a distinction is made, it is usually based on the fact that citizenship confers political rights. For ethnicity, use the concept 'ethnic group' (1202).</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5265</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5282</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>In accordance with the Cotonou Agreement, the resources and activities of the Centre for the Development of Industry (CDI) were transferred to the Centre for the Development of Enterprise (CDE) in August 2000.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5283</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN><HN>The United Kingdom ceased to be a Member State of the European Union on 31.01.2020.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5287</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Ionising radiation includes: X-rays, gamma rays, radiation from radioactive sources and sources of naturally occurring radiation, such as radon gas.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5291</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>To be used for social aspects of death and attitudes towards death.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5302</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5312</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>May be linked to the subject area concerned.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5313</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>To be used for a country or within an institution.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5328</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>New name of the Court of First Instance since the Lisbon Treaty came into force (1.12.2009).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5334</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>To be used for the transfer of information in a legal or ethical context.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5352</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>On 1 January 2016, the region of Centre was renamed Centre-Val de Loire.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5381</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>On 1 January 2016, the region of Champagne-Ardenne was incorporated into the region of Grand Est</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5393</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Drafted in 1948 in order to establish an International Trade Organisation but failed to enter into force.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5395</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>The European Social Charter, which guarantees social and economic human rights, was adopted by the Council of Europe in 1961. The 1996 revision came in to force in 1999.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5407</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use with "association agreement (EU)", "trade agreement (EU)" or "cooperation agreement (EU)".</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5409</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Agreements concluded jointly by the Member States and the European Communities in areas of shared responsibility.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5416</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Not to be confused with action to establish liability on the part of an administration.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5437</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5438</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Until 31.01.2020 regions of the United Kingdom were included among the regions of EU Member States.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5449</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for the parliamentary body of an international organisation.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5450</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for institutions.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5465</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for assets derived from an illicit activity, such as drug trafficking.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5478</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Superseded the NACC (North Atlantic Cooperation Council) in 1997. It brings together the member countries and partner countries of NATO, allowing them to discuss and confer on political and security matters.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5494</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Clause allowing a Member State to refrain from or to delay the application of certain provisions of an agreement.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5495</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>The Wassenaar Arrangement on Multilateral Export Controls for Conventional Arms and Dual-Use Goods and Technologies superseded the COCOM (Coordinating Committee for Multilateral Export Controls) in 1996.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5499</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The pursuit of balanced and sustainable development throughout the European Union.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5501</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Constitutes a local territorial area. Not to be confused with the descriptor "local government".</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5506</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>The Comitology Decision was repealed and replaced on 1 March 2011 by the Comitology Regulation.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5507</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>The Comitology Decision was repealed and replaced on 1 March 2011 by the Comitology Regulation.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5508</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>The denomination 'Committee of the Regions of the European Union’ is replaced by ‘European Committee of the Regions’ as from February 2017.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5511</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>On 1 March 2011, this Regulation repealed and replaced Comitology Decision 1999/468/EC and introduced two new procedures: an advisory procedure and an examination procedure. These procedures thus replace the advisory procedure, the management procedure and the regulatory procedure introduced by the Decision adopted in 1999.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5512</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for the legal or illegal trade in any part of the human body or any product derived therefrom.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5519</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Where appropriate, use in conjunction with the EU institution concerned.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5526</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>ILO governing body, made up of national delegations representing government, workers and employers.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5539</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>This is the fourth resource, introduced in 1988, and is based on GNP and the application of a rate, set under the budget procedure, to the total GNP of all the Member States.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5544</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Historical concept referring to cooperation in the field of justice and home affairs, which was subsequently incorporated into the Schengen Agreement and then into the institutional framework of the European Union. Use “AFSJ” (area of freedom, security and justice).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5598</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for matters relating to the legal bond between two or more persons, whereby one of them may compel the other to fulfil an obligation.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>56</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Not to be confused with public service accounting.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5609</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for the conditions of actual use of the various official languages.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5612</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for a worker's personal protective equipment and for safety devices on machines and equipment.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5614</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for equipment subjected to a positive or negative pressure compared to atmospheric pressure.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5640</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use also for EU bodies.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5655</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5656</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Intergovernmental group responsible for international monetary questions affecting the interests of developing countries.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5668</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Replaced on 1 January 2007 by the European Fisheries Fund (EFF).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5680</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>The European Monetary Institute (EMI) was established on 1 January 1994 at the start of the second stage of the Economic and Monetary Union (EMU). It was liquidated when the European Central Bank (ECB) was established on 1 June 1998.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5695</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>This designation is without prejudice to positions on status, and is in line with UNSCR 1244/1999 and the ICJ Opinion on the Kosovo declaration of independence.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5713</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>As of 12 February 2019, with the entry into force of the Prespa Agreement, the former Yugoslav Republic of Macedonia has been renamed the Republic of North Macedonia.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5719</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>When referring to the animal variant, use “BSE”.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5726</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Do not confuse with "EU trade mark".</SN><SN>The blue guide provides an overview of the interpretation of provisions relating to EU product rules.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5728</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Covers animal feed, fertilisers, pet food, leather and wool etc.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5734</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>For preference, use the generic term ‘veterinary medicinal product’.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5761</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Intergovernmental working groups supervised by the Council and responsible for matters concerning terrorism, internal security, police cooperation, organised crime and the free movement of persons. These groups no longer exist but prefigured the intergovernmental structure put in place by the Maastricht Treaty and the Schengen agreements.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5762</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for all entities which have the power of decision within an EU body.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5763</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for any body created under a European Union agreement and composed of representatives of the European Union and of one or more third countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5772</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Not to be confused with financial assistance provided under EU programmes and in accordance with EU policies.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5773</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Initiative aimed at improving stability and security in Europe by strengthening ties between NATO and the countries of Central and Eastern Europe or other States belonging to the CSCE.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5775</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5776</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5778</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5780</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5781</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>58</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Not to be confused with national accounts.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5805</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Not to be confused with “president of an institution”.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5806</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Not to be confused with Presidency of the European Council related to the concept 'President of the European Council' (439592). The Presidency of the Council of the EU relates directly to the Council of the EU (which negotiates and votes on EU legislation bringing together the ministers of the EU Member States) and not to the European Council (which sets the EU's political agenda bringing together the Heads of State or Government of each EU Member State).</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5815</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Replaced by the ordinary legislative procedure when the Lisbon Treaty came into force (1.12.2009).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5821</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for persons who treat patients by methods not recognised by conventional medicine.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5826</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for any campaign aimed at promoting the idea of European integration.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5835</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for an appeal to an administrative court. Not to be confused with an appeal to an administrative authority.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5848</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for geographical areas which are not confined within national frontiers.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5851</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for national and regional parliaments or assemblies.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5855</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for questions regarding the balanced division of powers between the EU, national and regional institutions.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5868</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>This comes from the application of a flat rate to the VAT base of each Member State.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5887</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Do not confuse with "aviation security".</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>58876</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The concept recognised non-citizen can refer to individuals who are permanent residents but do not hold citizenship due to historical factors related to the dissolution of the Soviet Union particularly in the Baltic countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5891</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for campaigns launched to inform the general public. Combine with the field in question or with the name of the institution if the campaign refers to the image which the general public has of this institution.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5897</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use to describe the politics of one country, a group of countries or a region at a specific time.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5903</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for a show or any other public event where animals are used.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5930</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>This designation shall not be construed as recognition of a State of Palestine and is without prejudice to the individual positions of the EU Member States on this issues.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>594</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>With effect from the signing of the Lomé Convention in 1975, use ACP countries.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5948</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Originated as informal consultation between the Member States in order to develop joint positions and jointly implement a European foreign policy. Enshrined in the Treaty on European Union, it was replaced by the common foreign and security policy. Use “CFSP”.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>596</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Until 31.01.2020 regions of the United Kingdom were included among the regions of EU Member States.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6034</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Covers various types of territorial area. Not to be confused with the descriptor "local government".</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6048</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>In 2008, as a consequence of the establishment of a single CMO (Common Market Organisation) regulation of the agricultural markets, the individual sector specific Management Committees were replaced by a single Management Committee for the Common Organisation of Agricultural Markets.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6050</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>The Comitology Decision was repealed and replaced on 1 March 2011 by the Comitology Regulation.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6052</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Not to be confused with food supplement.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6056</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Refers to committees whose French title contains the expression 'comité paritaire'.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6091</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Generic term for the three European standardisation bodies (CEN, Cenelec and ETSI). Use with each specific body.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6112</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>When referring to the human variant, use “disease of the nervous system”.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6114</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Group of seven most industrialised countries (US, Japan, Canada, France, Germany, Italy and the UK). When Russia joined in 1998, it became the “Group of Eight”.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6116</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Permanent mechanism for consultation and concerted political action for the countries of Latin America and the Caribbean, resulting from the merger of the Contadora Group and the Lima Group in 1986.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6128</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>With the entry into force of Regulation EU 2015/2424 amending the Community trade mark regulation on 23 March, OHIM became the European Union Intellectual Property Office (EUIPO), and the Community trade mark became the European Union trade mark.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6129</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Created in 1952 as the Customs Cooperation Council, the organisation was officially renamed the World Customs Organisation in 1994.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6130</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Dispute settlement system of the WTO which governments may resort to if they are of the conviction that certain rules or laws have not been respected.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6140</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Only to be used for documents of a very general nature, otherwise choose a more specific descriptor.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6146</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Agreement on Trade-Related Aspects of Intellectual Property Rights.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6148</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>The Confederation of European Business adopted the name “BusinessEurope” in January 2007.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6160</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Use for the Eutelsat intergovernmental organisation, which was created in 1977 to manage a satellite telecommunications infrastructure in Europe. In July 2001, Eutelsat’s activities were transferred to a company under private law.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6163</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Created in 1924 as the International Office of Epizootics, the organisation was officially renamed the World Organisation for Animal Health in 2003.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6192</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Computer peripheral for digitising text and image.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6205</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6219</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Replace the European Monitoring Centre on Racism and Xenophobia.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6223</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>On 4 February 2003 the State Union of Serbia and Montenegro superseded the Federal Republic of Yugoslavia, which had been proclaimed on 27 April 1992. On 3 June 2006 Montenegro declared independence and the Federal State split into two new independent States: the Republic of Serbia and the Republic of Montenegro.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6253</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>The Social Policy Agreement has been incorporated into the EC Treaty by the Treaty of Amsterdam. The Social Policy Agreement sets out the EU's social policy objectives, whereby special emphasis has been put on equal opportunities and the fight against social exclusion.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>62714</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use to cover the following topics: coaches and coaching in the workplace, tutors in the workplace, mentors and mentoring in the workplace</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6284</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use with name of relevant institution.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6288</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>The office of High Representative of the Union for Foreign Affairs and Security Policy was instituted by the Lisbon Treaty (which came into force on 1.12.2009).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6298</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Rate of output which a worker is expected to maintain in order to receive a specific wage. Do not confuse with "labour standard".</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6311</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Refers to the division and ownership of land.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6327</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>The objective of EFICS is to collect, coordinate, standardise, process and disseminate information concerning the forestry sector.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6333</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>The ECU was a basket currency made up of the sum of fixed amounts of 12 of the 15 currencies of the EC Member States. The value of the ECU was calculated as a weighted average of the value of its component currencies. The ECU was replaced by the euro on a one-for-one basis on 1 January 1999.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6335</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Rate of parity between the euro and national currencies joining the euro zone. Fixed and irrevocable since 01.01.1999.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6347</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>This strategy was introduced after the adoption of the Treaty of Amsterdam to create jobs and fight unemployment.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6356</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use to indicate a change of job within the same company as a result of redeployment or promotion.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6369</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Not to be confused with the descriptor "public service", which refers to the body providing a service.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6373</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>In 2008, the Union for the Mediterranean replaced the Euro-Mediterranean partnership formerly known as the "Barcelona Process". The partnership brings together the 27 Member States of the European Union and 16 partner countries from the South Mediterranean region and the Middle East. After Croatia joining the EU (2013), the UfM comprises the 28 EU Member States, the European Commission and 15 Mediterranean countries.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6559</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Applies only to the sense of belonging to the European Union.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6569</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Not to be confused with food security that refers to access to food for all.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6627</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Not in the sense of theological debates.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>663</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Until 31.01.2020 regions of the United Kingdom were included among the regions of EU Member States.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>665</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Single European currency introduced in January 1999, the name of which was decided on at the Madrid European Council in December 1995. To be used instead of the generic term 'ecu' after 01.01.1999.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6704</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Not to be used in the context of the European Union.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6709</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Replaces the European security and defence policy  from the entry into force of the Treaty of Lisbon (1.12.2009).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6711</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>The European Consumer Centres Network (ECC-Net) was established in January 2005 after the merger of two existing consumer protection networks: the Network for the extra-judicial settlement of consumer disputes (EEJ-Net) and the Euroguichet Network.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6725</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Use after 1 November 1993, date on which the Treaty of Maastricht came into force.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6789</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Not to be confused with food additive.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>68</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use only for local administrations. Not to be confused with the descriptors "regional and local authorities" and "local authority".</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6852</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for indexing global satellite systems used for navigation and positioning.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6892</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use to index documents concerning the linguistic and legislative qualities of a law.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6901</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for the sale of products from machines. For "automatic teller machine", use the descriptor "electronic banking".</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>695</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use specific terms.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>7134</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for the economies of countries which abandoned the communist system in 1989 in order to adopt an alternative system.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>7136</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Not to be confused with "services of general interest" or "public service".</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>7137</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Not to be confused with the “International Criminal Court” or the “International Court of Justice”.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>7185</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Free-trade agreement set up in 1992 by three central European countries (Czechoslovakia, Poland and Hungary) and bringing together EU partner countries and countries seeking EU membership. At 1 January 2007, the members of CEFTA were Croatia, the Former Yugoslav Republic of Macedonia, Serbia, Montenegro, Albania, Bosnia and Herzegovina, Moldova and Kosovo.
Croatia withdrew following its accession to the EU in July 2013.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>7193</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Not to be confused with the International Criminal Tribunal (for Rwanda and the former Yugoslavia) and the International Court of Justice of the United Nations, which deals primarily with disputes between States.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>7194</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>As of the entry into force of the Lisbon Treaty (01.12.2009), use "decision (EU)".</HN><HN>Term used with regard to the area of freedom, security and justice (AFSJ).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>7198</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>A State in Oceania comprising more than 600 islands in the archipelago of the Caroline Islands, with four constituent States: Chuuk, Kosrae, Pohnpei (Ponape) and Yap.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>7207</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>7212</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for the drafting of administrative documents.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>7221</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>End of mandate: 31.12.2008.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>73</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Introduced in the 1970s, the medium-term financial assistance (MTFA) and Community loan mechanisms provided mutual financial support for Member States facing serious balance-of-payments difficulties. In 1988, they were merged into the balance-of-payments facility. From 2002, this financial assistance has been for Member States that have not adopted the euro.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>7378</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>In a regional context; not to be confused with "autonomist party".</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>744</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Energy which is non-pollutant, whether renewable or not.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>7813</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Agreement signed on 23 June 2000, for a period of 20 years with a clause providing for a review every five years, between the 15 EU member States and 76 African, Caribbean and Pacific (ACP) countries. This Agreement succeeds takes the place of the Lomé Agreements, which had governed relations between the EU and the ACP countries since 1975.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>7938</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>On 27 June 2019 the European Cybersecurity Act entered into force, setting the new mandate of ENISA. EUR-Lex. </HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>7985</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Until 14.6.2016: ‘European Railway Agency’ (ERA).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>7986</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Until 30.6.2016: ‘European Police College’ (CEPOL).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>81270</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The concept "Anthropocene" is still considered informal and is not universally recognised as an official unit within the geological time scale. Researchers and scientists continue to debate its precise starting point and formal recognition in geological terms.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>820</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>To be used in combination with market sectors.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>82377</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>It does not necessarily mean biodegradable or compostable.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>8278</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>8279</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Created on 01/01/2007, the region comprises the former counties of Copenhagen and Frederiksborg, the municipalities of Copenhagen and Frederiksberg, and the municipal regional municipality of Bornholm.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>8280</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Created on 01/01/2007, the region comprises the former counties of Ringkjøbing and Århus, plus part of the counties of Viborg and Vejle.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>8281</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Created on 01/01/2007, the region comprises the former county of Nordjylland (North Jutland), plus part of the county of Viborg.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>8282</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Created on 01/01/2007, the region comprises the former counties of Roskilde, Storstrøm and Vestsjælland.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>8283</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Created on 01/01/2007, the region comprises the former counties of Fyns, Ribe and Sønderjylland (South Jutland), plus part of the county of Vejle.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>8284</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Until 31.12.2011: ‘Community Fisheries Control Agency’ (CFCA).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>8357</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>This designation is without prejudice to positions on status, and is in line with UNSCR 1244/1999 and the ICJ Opinion on the Kosovo declaration of independence.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>8365</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>8366</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>8367</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>8369</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>8386</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Regional commission of the United Nations Economic and Social Council (Ecosoc), which initiates measures to promote regional economic development and to strengthen economic relations between countries.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>8393</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Joint and Co-sponsored United Nations Programme on HIV and AIDS (JCP/UNAIDS).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>8396</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Political forum for regional and intergovernmental cooperation between 11 countries in the Baltic Sea region (Denmark, Estonia, Finland, Germany, Iceland, Latvia, Lithuania, Norway, Poland, Russia, Sweden) and the European Commission.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>8400</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Preferential trade area for the countries of East Africa and Southern Africa.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>8404</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>The ITUC was created on 1 November 2006, superseding the International Confederation of Free Trade Unions (ICFTU) and the World Confederation of Labour (WCL).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>8407</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>After the reform of the Staff Regulations of Officials of the European Communities in May 2004, the old “B”, “C” and “D” categories were replaced by the assistants’ function group “AST”.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>8439</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Until 5.10.2016: ‘European Agency for the Management of Operational Cooperation at the External Borders of the Member States of the European Union’.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>8458</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use with “lay magistrate” (challenge to a juror), “evidence” (challenge to a witness) or “judge” (challenge to a judge).</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>8462</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>The Civil Service Tribunal, established in 2004, ceased to operate on 1 September 2016 after its jurisdiction was transferred to the General Court.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>8465</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use with the institution, body or agency concerned.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>8474</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>With the entry into force of the Treaty of Lisbon (1.12.2009), common strategies in the area of freedom, security and justice and the common foreign and security policy have been replaced by decisions of the Council. Use (EU) decision.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>8481</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Police force established under the European Security and Defence Policy which takes part in international civilian crisis management operations and in conflict prevention.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>8488</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Created in 2001 from the merger of the International Union for Inland Navigation (IUIN) and the Rhine International Navigation Consortium.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>8498</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Until 31.01.2020 regions of the United Kingdom were included among the regions of EU Member States.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>8542</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>After the reform of the Staff Regulations of Officials of the European Communities in May 2004, the old “A” and “LA” categories were replaced by the administrators’ function group “AD”.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>8553</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>The Lisbon Treaty, which came into force on 1 December 2009, amalgamates the European Union and the European Community into a single European Union. The terms "European Union" and "EU" replace "European Community", "Community" and "EC".</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>908</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Informal association of the Ministers of Defence of European NATO countries. It was dissolved in 1994.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>91584</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The acronym 'LGBTQ' may evolve over time to include additional letters to represent other identities. This concept aims to cover all relevant identities and orientations not included in the acronym.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>92284</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Education admission requirements include examination certificates, proof of skills, etc.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>972</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use this and specific terms for wild animals, either at liberty or in captivity.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>978</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use only in cases where EAGGF is understood in a general sense without distinguishing between Guidance and Guarantee Sections.</SN><HN>Replaced, since 1 January 2007, by the European Agricultural Fund for Rural Development (EAFRD) and European Agricultural Guarantee Fund (EAGF).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>979</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>On 1 January 2007, this fund was replaced by the European Agricultural Guarantee Fund (EAGF).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>980</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>On 1 January 2007, this fund was replaced by the European Agricultural Fund for Rural Development (EAFRD).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_047e5912</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>The EBA was established on 1 January 2011 as part of the European System of Financial Supervision (ESFS) and took over all existing responsibilities and tasks of the Committee of European Banking Supervisors.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_058697c2</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>These include individual lifestyle factors such as diet and smoking, social and community networks, and general socioeconomic, cultural, and environmental conditions.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_062f6587</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Entered in force on 27 September 2012. The ESM has taken over the tasks fulfilled by the European Financial Stability Facility (EFSF) and the European Financial Stabilisation Mechanism (EFSM).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_0a700c19</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Region formed by the merger of the regions of Auvergne and Rhône-Alpes on 1 January 2016.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_1c478aa5</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Do not confuse with "sanction (EU)". EU restrictive measure involves measures taken against non-EU entities.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_1c7d7d1e</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>More specifically, it involves child care, elder care, education, healthcare, and personal social and domestic services that are provided in both paid and unpaid forms and within formal and informal sectors.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_2b2e17b1</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_2c8a75b1</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Not to be confused with family migration.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_2d0e694e</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>The Economic and Financial Committee was preceded by the Monetary Committee.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_2e7c1ac5</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>This designation shall not be construed as recognition of a State of Palestine and is without prejudice to the individual positions of the Member States on this issue.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_348000be</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>It is accepted as the most useful indicator of obesity in adults.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_39cda9ba</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Biocides are commonly used in medicine, agriculture, forestry, and industry.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_3f9a7b14</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Not to be confused with erosion that excludes mass wasting.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_449d36c3</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Not to be confused with withdrawal.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_4c7717f3</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Term introduced in 2018; prior to that use public contract.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_4e3beee2</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Replaces the European Fisheries Fund’ (EFF) established for the period 2007-2013.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_505c95bd</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>It is determined by the degree to which the social system is capale of organizing itself to increase its capacity for learning from past disasters or better future protection and to improve risk reduction measures.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_50620749</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>The European Voluntary Service, established in 1996, was replaced by the newly launched European Solidarity Corps in 2016, which is an expanded version of the program.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_525f45d9</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The factors can be a combination of low income, high energy expenditure and low energy efficiency of the homes.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_6741b0ee</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>MSDs can arise from a sudden exertion (e.g., lifting a heavy object), or they can arise from making the same motions repeatedly repetitive strain, or from repeated exposure to force, vibration, or awkward posture and affect many different parts of the body including upper and lower back, neck, shoulders and extremities (arms, legs, feet, and hands).</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_6e3cbbca</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Covers activities such as yachting, cruising or water sports and the operation of landside facilities, manufacturing of equipment, and services necessary for it.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_71b063b1</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Member States have an obligation to designate competent authorities under most of EU directives and regulations and to notify them to the European Commission.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_777eba81</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Entered into force on 1 January 2013.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_791e9f27</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Region formed by the merger of the regions of Languedoc-Roussillon and Midi-Pyrénées on 1 January 2016.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_814bb9e4</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use generally for diseases caused by any type of the coronavirus family.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_8331ae25</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Region formed by the merger of the regions of Lower and Upper Normandy on 1 January 2016.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_871b5612</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use this concept for questions concerning staff regulations and rules for EU civil servants.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_8bf65f26</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The main components are mobile internet access, social media use, e-commerce, internet security, cloud services, digital skills.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_8d31aed6</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Encompasses fields as diverse as fisheries, maritime transports and marine environment.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_90dfa6c7</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The term is used only to refer to cash transfers or vouchers given to individuals, households or communities, not to governments or to other state actors. This excludes remittances and microfinance in humanitarian interventions.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_964c9649</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_96af33df</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>There is no international legal definition of hate speech. The terms 'hate speech' and 'incitement to hatred' are often used synonymously. However, from a legal perspective, hate speech has to reach a certain threshold before it can be considered incitement and a criminal offence.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_977a9fe5</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Not to be confused with temporary migration.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_9eb9cbaa</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Not to be confused with expatriate worker.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_a02d5941</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Established in 1999 to discuss key issues for global economic stability.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_a18a0eda</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>It existed from 1952 until 1957.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_af502da0</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>To be  used in combination with with the domain concerned by the alert.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_b0536152</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Not to be confused with occupational migration.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_b0d2dfd4</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>It considered a seed (vegetable) but is eaten like a grain.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_b18ab65c</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>To be  used in combination with a sector.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_b1ac7db6</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>It includes aspects such as web design, web publishing, web programming, and database management.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_b605a1d4</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Established by the General Assembly resolution 60/251 of 15 March 2006 as one of its subsidiary bodies, in replacement of the Commission on Human Rights'.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_b71ca500</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Do not confuse with decontamination which applies to pollution.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_ba4acdb2</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>It might include psychological consultation, cross-hormonal treatment, sex or gender reassignment surgery (GRS) (such as facial surgery, chest/breast surgery, different kinds of genital surgery, or a hysterectomy), sterilisation (leading to infertility), hair removal and voice training. Not every transgender person wishes for, or is able to undergo, all or any of these measures.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_bbd07d89</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Region formed by the merger of the regions of Nord-Pas-de-Calais and Picardy on 1 January 2016.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_be8fda35</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Region formed by the merger of the regions of Aquitaine, Limousin and Poitou-Charentes on 1 January 2016.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_c385cfb4</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_c44f1704</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Region formed by the merger of the regions of Alsace, Champagne-Ardenne and Lorraine on 1 January 2016.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_c4afa011</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Do not confuse with the pharmaceutical industry.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_c8363c09</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Should preferably be used in conjunction with the policy or sector concerned.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_c8c80a5b</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Do not confuse with "air safety".</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_d0e30aa9</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>This partnership also includes the EEA and EFTA countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_d1c21de0</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Lithium and its compounds have several industrial applications, including heat-resistant glass and ceramics, lithium grease lubricants, flux additives for iron, steel and aluminium production, lithium batteries, and lithium-ion batteries. It is also used as a mood stabilizer and antidepressant in the treatment of mental illness such as bipolar disorder.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_d6e0eb67</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>It includes the continuity of the bank’s critical functions, financial stability and minimal costs to taxpayers.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_dcc650ef</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for investment funds (non-harmonised funds) not regulated by the UCITS directive.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_de4d6f2f</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Combine with the related sectors or industries. Do not confuse with "technology park".</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_e0543dcb</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>It can include sexual, physical, mental and economic harm inflicted in public or in private.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_e0e4608a</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Not to be confused with nuclear safety: security is concerned with the issue of criminal acts; safety is concerned with the issue undue radiation hazards.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_e14565e5</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>They comprise personal traits, attitudes and motivations.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_ee706406</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>It may also include articles which may foreseeably come into contact with food.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_f2f1fb47</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Region formed by the merger of the regions of Burgundy and Franche-Comté on 1 January 2016.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_f7c1b2bd</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Dynamic data is contrasted with static data.</SN></RECORD></SCOPE_NOTE>